# **AMIT LAD**

10 NETHERLANDS ROAD, NEW BARNET, HERTFORDSHIRE, EN5 1BN TELEPHONE: 020 8441 1740 MOBILE: 07828 824 001

E-MAIL: AMIT.R.LAD@GMAIL.COM WEBSITE: WWW.AMITLAD.CO.UK

I am a multi-skilled person that is able to communicate, handle responsibility and use initiative in order to complete tasks and meet deadlines. I have proven experience working in administrative, practical and technical environments both on my own and as part of a team. I am interested in a career as an Actuary, as I think I will be able to apply my skills to excel in this role.

#### Education

#### Warwick University

October 2007 - Present

- Currently 4th year undergraduate reading Mathematics (Hons).
- Expected 1st (Hons) Degree.
- Have taken modules in Pure mathematics, Mechanics, Statistics and Economics.
- Supervising 1st year undergraduates during my final year.

#### The Latymer School, Enfield

**September 2000 - June 2007** 

- A-Levels 4 A's including Maths, Physics and Economics.
- GCSEs 7 A\*'s and 3 A's including English, Maths and Science.

## **Employment History**

#### Coordinator, Warwick Nightline

February 2010 - February 2011

- Volunteer position, running a team of 92 student volunteers to provide a peer support listening service for the students at Warwick University.
- Successfully ran a training weekend to recruit new members to this organisation. Through various publicity, training and team working efforts, managed to get **28 new volunteers** the most that have ever joined in one training session since our records began.
- Improved overall member participation by implementing an electronic membership and night duty sign-up system.
- Main responsibilities involve:
  - 1. Ensuring that the service is available for every night of term.
  - 2. Looking after the welfare of our volunteers.
  - 3. Organising our Executive committee and supporting them to develop and move the organisation forwards.

#### Summer Internship, Metaswitch Networks

**July 2010 - September 2010** 

- Main tasks included:
  - 1. Created a suite of functional verification tests for a new product. Improved the code coverage of product from 42% to 92%.
  - 2. Performance tested a new product and investigated differences between estimates made beforehand and test results. Identified and highlighted a major performance, meaning that the design had plenty of time to tackle the issue.
- Improved technical skills in order to complete tasks.
- Produced methodical, well documented work so that test results were easier to analyse. Gave
  presentation of the results of my investigation so that people knew about areas for
  improvement.

#### Summer Internship, Barnett Waddingham LLP

July 2009 - August 2009

Working within the Insurance Consulting team

- Given introductions to the various tasks that actuaries in the office were performing.
- Main task focused on marketing and gathering various information about potential clients.

#### Summer Internship, Data Connection

July 2008 - August 2008

- Main tasks included:
  - 1. Created an automated testing environment for a specific product. **Achieved 100**% **functional verification**.
  - 2. Enhanced functions and developed new tools for the Subversion Code Management System **used by 70+ people in the company** on a daily basis.
  - 3. Researched and implemented the upgrade of the core Subversion servers from v1.3 to v1.5.
- Rapidly learnt technical skills in order to use them to complete tasks.
- Produced quality work under the pressure of time, since the systems I was often working on were used by a large number of my colleagues. As such, the consequences for taking too long, or getting anything wrong were quite drastic.
- Communicated my work to others working on similar systems/projects so that our work wouldn't interfere or overlap.
- Documented and gave a presentation on my work so that people knew what to do once I had left.

#### Assistant Scout Leader, 4th East Barnet Sea Scouts

June 2006 - Present

- Volunteer position working with a small **team of five people** to help run a local scout group.
- Planning and running a varied and interesting programme for the 30 scouts registered in our group on a weekly basis.
- Helping to run climbing and water sports activities as I am trained to do so. Me helping out allows 8 extra scouts to participate.
- Helping to organise and execute larger events such as week long camps for up to 30 scouts and expeditions for groups of 4-5 scouts.
- Also lightly involved with budgeting and fundraising for the group.
- CRB cleared to work with young people.

#### Learning Assistant, Kumon Education

November 2003 - August 2007

- Helping tuition students with English and Maths study material.
- Marking test papers and maintaining progress reports for parents.

#### Achievements and Skills

- Qualified First Aider (valid until September 2009).
- Trainee Kayaking and Canoeing Instructor (with the Scout Association).
- Trained Climbing Instructor (with the Scout Association).
- Attained the Duke of Edinburgh's Gold Award and Queen's Scout Award.

### Referees

Available on Request